Mary Donovan Martello

5107 Jackson Street, Omaha, NE 68106 Phone: (402) 305-4633 E-mail: mdonovanmartello@gmail.com

Profile

I was a lawyer and a CPA for 26 years, but I earned a Masters in Data Science through Bellevue University in June of 2021 and I have been studying data science and computer programming since May of 2018. I am now seeking employment in the data science industry. I also volunteer as a teaching assistant for Mystery Code Society and training hotels on sex trafficking for the Coalition on Human Trafficking.

Objective

To obtain a full-time data scientist position utilizing my analytical, problem-solving, programming and statistical skills.

Portfolio: https://marydonovanmartello.github.io/

Highlighted skills and knowledge include:

- Python and R
- Data mining
- Predictive analytics
- Data wrangling and exploration
- Deep learning
- Data Visualization
- Statistics
- COBOL
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript

- Accounting/financial/ tax analysis
- Writing and speaking skills
- Research a
- Excel spreadsheets

Experience

Self-Employed – Estate and Business Planning Attorney

- Negotiate with taxing authorities
- Conduct trust accounting and reformation proceedings
- Analyze and reconcile entity accountings and reports
- Design complex estate and business plans
- Administer estates and trusts

Dvorak & Donovan Law Group, LLC

Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

Founding Member and Equity Partner

- Managed financial and business aspects of the firm
- Led estate planning and administration practice
- Designed complex estate and business plans
- Trained and developed attorneys

February 2017 - Present

January 2015 – February 2017

Resume: Mary Donovan Martello

August 1999 - January 2015

Koley Jessen, P.C. L.L.O.

Attorney – Estate and Business Planning

Equity Partner/Associate Attorney

• Same duties as listed in above legal jobs

Nelson, Morrow & Waldron Law Office Attorney – Estate and Business Planning March 1998 - August 1999

• Same duties as listed in above legal jobs

Coopers & Lybrand L.L.P. (National Accounting Firm) September 1995 – April 1998 Certified Public Accountant

- Obtained a Certified Public Accountant license
- Researched and planned for corporate, partnership and individual taxation issues
- Researched business and estate planning issues
- Drafted correspondence to the Internal Revenue Service and state departments of revenue
- Prepared and reviewed tax returns

Education

Bellevue University, Bellevue, Nebraska

Masters in Data Science Nov 2019 – June

Business Analytics Certificate 2021

Python, R Programming, EDA, Data Mining, Predictive Analytics

Nov 2018 – Feb 2019

GPA: 4.0

AIM Institute/Interface: The Web School, Omaha, Nebraska

Interface COBOL Course

COBOL Sept – Dec 2018

Midland University Code Academy, Omaha, Nebraska

Web Foundations

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript

May – August 2018

Creighton University School of Law, Omaha, Nebraska

Juris Doctor

Emphasis on tax and estate planning courses

May 1995 Magna Cum Laude

Creighton University – College of Business, Omaha, Nebraska

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Business/Law Accelerated Program – Emphasis on accounting courses

May 1993 Summa Cum Laude GPA: 4.0

Class rank: 9/155

Volunteer Activity

- Mystery Code Society (Teaching Assistant)
- Coalition on Human Trafficking
- Omaha Morning Rotary (Past President /Treasurer)
- Former TeamMates Mentor